<resources>
    <string name="app_name">VoiceHacker Accents</string>
    <string name="app_name_free">VoiceHacker Accents (Free)</string>
    <string name="app_name_pro">VoiceHacker Accents (Pro)</string>
    <string name="preference_file_key">app.voicehacker.co.uk.PREFERENCE_FILE_KEY</string>
    <string name="importedconsonantsstarred">app.voicehacker.co.uk.CONSONANTS_STARRED</string>
    <string name="importedvowelsstarred">app.voicehacker.co.uk.VOWELS_STARRED</string>
    <string name="importedpremstarred">app.voicehacker.co.uk.PREMIUM_STARRED</string>
    <string name="purchased001">app.voicehacker.co.uk.PURCHASED_001</string>
    <string name="tutorialviewed">app.voicehacker.co.uk.TUTORIAL_VIEWED</string>
    <string name="promotext">Get access to 1,000 practice word recordings, 3,000 words of descriptions and a whole new front page of advanced material. All it takes is a couple of clicks - no download required. Jumpstart your accent learning and nail your pronunciation. Just press ‘unlock’ to head to the Google Play Store.</string>
    <string name="promopreview">You\'ve found a premium feature! Get access to over 3,000 words of descriptions and 1,000 words of recordings by unlocking our premium package.</string>
    <string name="discountcode001">ARTHURLESSAC01</string>

    <string name="key1">MIIBIjANBgkqhkiG9w0B</string>
    <string name="key2">AQEFAAOCAQ8AMIIBCgKCAQEAjbBugXuIHsnf</string>
    <string name="key3">+BhvSFfycgZKdlJJyrg8gx2039fCVh8HjttGZvZwctUs64p0WOC</string>
    <string name="key4">ylfri5uTDvwxer3eT6iLY</string>
    <string name="key5">dBOBIN77arxKMhktPLKFQ+5h9EfkE9w9/wFMQwb+</string>
    <string name="key6">uo8CTdFLWg+i2YQk9gPXLsv6sbZ96JpZ</string>
    <string name="key7">ubipxvGXI6xtD9DXCsItzf5HUBPty5BcDDath6zL7T4mSn</string>
    <string name="key8">g295uFxZA0DY3jLbeBhTwIkq/xnoebNcRKbSzIQl</string>
    <string name="key9">5o5GDIXlRl6uBNlMMrLHTQZ7kD+caE7Ap7e1mIzxuwVDR</string>
    <string name="key10">b+ornpyLMpW7+ieCxS7TLJZvvAWI5CAu3aNtU</string>
    <string name="key11">W7UTPvD2oQOcu76hDQIDAQAB</string>



    <string name="desc_morecoming">There‘s more to say about this sound, so future updates will add more descriptions.</string>
    <string name="desc_diphthongs">Some vowels, like the ‘long’ and ‘short’ ones, choose one position and stick to it throughout. On the word ‘see’, your mouth finds a static position when it hits the ‘ee’, and holds it until the word is done. Diphthongs are vowels which move from one position to another. The vowel /eɪ/ (in ‘say’) starts with an /e/ (in ‘set’) and ends with an /ɪ/ (in ‘sit’). Diphthongs glide from one place to another, like “saaaayyyyy”. Some are obvious, like the ‘ah’ and ‘oo’ in the /aʊ/ in ‘mouth’. Some are more subtle, such as the sliding /eə/ in ‘chair’. Try to feel the beginning and end point of the diphthong vowel in the words above.</string>
    <string name="desc_shortvowels">Short vowels are - no surprises - short. They are quick, sharp, and punchy. When you emphasise a word with a short vowel, you emphasise the consonants, not the vowel. It’s the difference between ‘seat’ and ‘sit’. “Have a seeeeaat!”. “Just sssssit.” Try saying the words sharply, with more emphasis on the consonants.</string>
    <string name="desc_longvowels">Long vowels are - unsurprisingly - long. They are slow, gliding and smooth. When you emphasise a word with a long vowel, you emphasise the vowel, not the consonants which surround it. It’s the difference between ‘foot’ and ‘food’. “My ffffoot!.” “Have some foooood!”. Try making the words above longer, elongating the vowel.</string>
    <string name="desc_openjaw">This vowel uses an open jaw. The mouth should feel quite far open, and may feel quite weird for some speakers. The top and bottom front teeth should be two-three fingers’ widths apart. Try saying the vowel with two or three fingers between your teeth.</string>
    <string name="desc_midjaw">This vowel uses a semi-open jaw. The mouth should feel fairly neutral, as though it were at rest. The top and bottom front teeth should be one finger’s width apart. Try saying the vowel with one finger held between your teeth.</string>
    <string name="desc_closedjaw">This vowel uses a nearly closed jaw. The jaw should be very close to closed, but with a small gap between the teeth. The jaw should be slightly open, but too closed for you to fit a finger between the gap between your teeth.</string>
    <string name="desc_roundedlips">This vowel uses a rounded lip position. The lips should be puckered forward, creating a circular shape far further forward than their normal position. Imagine blowing out a candle, with the lips creating a funnel to direct the air forward. Place your fingers at the corner of your mouth. When you make the sound, you should notice the muscles in the lips working and pushing the mouth forwards.</string>
    <string name="desc_neutrallips">This mouth uses a neutral lip position. The lips should be totally relaxed. This may feel very strange for some accents. But for this sound, the lazier the lips, the better sound you get. Even the muscles around the lips are totally relaxed. Try making the sound and massaging the lips with your fingers to stop the lips overworking.</string>
    <string name="desc_spreadlips">This mouth uses a spread lip position. The lips should be engaged upwards and sideways into a smile. In a mirror, you should notice that you can see lots of your top row of teeth. Try making the sound with your fingers feeling the muscles between your lips and your cheekbones. There should be a sensation of muscles working gently below your fingers.</string>
    <string name="desc_placementback">This vowel should feel as though it is resonating at the back of the mouth. Compare it to the /iː/ sound (‘ee’), which should feel very far forward. The /ə/ sound (the ‘a’ in ‘comma’), in contrast, should feel very neutral and central. For the sound above, you should notice that the tongue feels engaged in a downward direction, with the sound resonating deep in the throat.
</string>
    <string name="desc_placementcentral">This vowel should feel as though it is resonating at the centre of the mouth. Compare it to the /iː/ sound (‘ee’), which should feel very far forward. The /ɔː/ (‘or’) sound, in contrast, should feel very far back. For the sound above, you should notice that the tongue feels very relaxed and neutral, with the tongue tip touching behind the bottom row of teeth.
</string>
    <string name="desc_placementfront">This vowel should feel as though it is resonating at the front of the mouth. Compare it to the /ə/ sound (the ‘a’ in ‘comma’), which should feel quite central. The /ɔː/ (‘or’) sound, in contrast, feels very far back. For the sound above, you should notice that the tongue feels engaged in a forward direction, with the tongue tip touching behind the bottom row of teeth.
</string>
    <string name="desc_fricatve">A fricative is a consonant that uses air pressure and friction to create sound. On each fricative, you blow out air and create friction by placing together two parts of the mouth. For the /f/ sound, the lower lip and the teeth come together. For the /s/ sound, the tongue creates friction just behind the upper teeth. Fricatives can be dragged out, and can last a long time, such as in “ssssssssooooo”. Other consonants, like plosives, are harder and can’t be dragged. Try extending and dragging out the fricative consonant in the words above.</string>
    <string name="desc_plosive">Plosives are explosions. They use a build-up of pressure, then an explosive release, to create sound. For a /p/ sound, the pressure builds behind the lips, then releases all at once in a ‘pop’. For a ‘t’ sound, the pressure builds between the tongue and the top teeth, then does the same. They are different from fricatives, which have no build-up of pressure. Plosives are punchier and sharper. On the words above, try making the plosive consonants sharper and punchier.</string>
    <string name="desc_affricate">Affricates are mixes between plosives and fricatives. They have the explosive quality of the plosives, and the dragged-out quality of the fricatives. The /tʃ/ (‘ch’) sound is a mix between a /t/ and a /ʃ/ (‘sh’), with the strong start of the ‘t’ and the longer ending of the ‘sh’. The /dʒ/ (‘j’) sound is a mix between the /d/ and the /ʒ/ (‘zh’ in measure). Make sure the affricates feel punchier than the fricatives - hit them hard at the beginnings.</string>
    <string name="desc_nasal">Most sounds are created in the throat, and leave through the mouth. But nasal consonants are different. They are the only sounds which leave through the nose, creating a distinctive muffled sound. Try closing one nostril with your finger and making a /m/ (‘mmm’) sound. You will feel the vibrations on your finger. Now try a /d/ (‘duh’) sound. You should feel far less vibration, or none at all. Keep your finger on your nose, and try to feel the nasality of each of the consonants above.</string>
    <string name="desc_approximant">Most consonants create sound by touching something to something else. For the /f/, the lower lips touch the teeth. But approximants don’t use contact: they move muscles closer to each other, narrowing the vocal tract to create the sound. They don’t touch, they approximate. For the /w/, the lips narrow at the front of the mouth. For the /r/, the tongue bunches up and approximates to the roof of the mouth. The /l/ and /ɫ/ (‘light’ and ‘still’) create narrowing by touching the roof of the mouth with the tongue. Try each sound in the words above, noticing the mouth and throat narrowing at the crucial moment.</string>
    <string name="desc_voiced">Voiced consonants use vocal fold vibration to make the sound. That means that, when you say this consonant, you should be feeling vibrations inside your throat. Take a finger and place it on your throat, and make a ‘mmm’ sound. You should feel a humming sensation. Next, make the sound above. You should feel the same sensation. Try the words above, feeling the vibrations on each voiced sound.</string>
    <string name="desc_unvoiced">Unvoiced consonants use no vocal fold vibration to make the sound. That means that, when you say this consonant you should feel no vibrations in the throat. Take a finger and place it on your throat, and make a ‘shh’ sound. You should feel no vibrations on the throat, unlike the voiced consonants such as ‘mmm’, which vibrate heavily. Try the words above, noticing the lack of vibration.</string>
    <string name="desc_thsound">The TH sound is a dental fricative - ‘dental’ meaning ‘teeth’. That means it makes sound by creating friction on the teeth. Place your tongue on your top teeth, and blow out air through your mouth. Try and direct the air to the point of friction, between your top teeth and your tongue.</string>
    <string name="desc_szsounds">The /s/ and /z/ sounds are alveolar fricatives - ‘alveolar’ referring to the ‘alveolar ridge’ in the roof of the mouth. That means they make sound by creating friction on the alveolar ridge. Try and feel where it is with your tongue - it’s on top of the mouth, just behind your top teeth. This is where the tongue goes when it makes the /s/ and /z/ sounds. The tongue rests close to the ridge, causing friction as you blow air through it. See if you can feel the tongue there when you make the sound.</string>
    <string name="desc_fvsounds">The /f/ and /v/ sounds are labiodental fricatives - ‘labio’ referring to the lips, and ‘dental’ meaning ‘teeth’. That means they make sound by creating friction by touching the lips to the teeth. In this case, that’s the lower lip to the upper teeth. Try the sound above, curling up the lower lip to touch the top teeth. Try directing air through the gap to create friction. That’s how you make the sound.</string>
    <string name="desc_hsound">The /h/ sound is a glottal fricative - ‘glottal’ referring to the ‘glottis’, the space between your vocal folds. The vocal folds are inside your larynx, which is the part of your throat which sticks out at the front. The /h/ makes sound by creating friction inside the larynx by blowing air through. Simply blowing out air from a relaxed mouth is enough to create a /h/.</string>
    <string name="desc_shzhsounds">The /ʃ/, /ʒ/, /tʃ/ and /dʒ/ sounds are palato-alveolar consonants. ‘Palato’ refers to the ‘hard palate’, otherwise known as the roof of your mouth. ‘Alveolar’ refers to the ‘alveolar ridge’, the ridge near the front of the roof of your mouth. These sounds are made by creating friction on the hard palate, just behind the ridge. Try to feel where the ridge is with your finger - just behind the teeth. When you make the sound above, your tongue should feel like it hangs around that area, creating friction by its presence.</string>
    <string name="desc_pbsounds">The /p/ and /b/ sounds are bilabial plosives - ‘bilabial’ referring to your two (from ‘bi’) lips (from ‘labial’). You make the sounds by building up air pressure behind the lips, which explodes to create a ‘plosive’. Try building up air pressure behind the lips to make the sound above.</string>
    <string name="desc_tdsounds">The /t/ and /d/ are alveolar plosives - ‘alveolar’ referring to the ‘alveolar ridge’, the ridge near the front of the roof of your mouth. That means you make the sounds by touching the tongue to the roof of the mouth, creating a seal, and building up pressure behind the seal. When you release the pressure, the air explodes out, making the sound. Try placing your tongue at the ridge to make the sound above.</string>
    <string name="desc_kgsounds">The /k/ and /g/ are velar plosives - ‘velar’ referring to the soft palate (or ‘velum’), the soft ridge of muscle at the back of the mouth. You can feel the velum by running your finger along the roof of your mouth until you feel some soft muscle at the back of the throat. You make the /k/ and /g/ sound by connecting the velum to the back of the tongue, creating a seal, and building up air pressure behind the seal. When you release the pressure, the air explodes out, making the sound.</string>
    <string name="desc_msounds">The /m/ is a bilabial nasal - ‘bilabial’ referring to your two (from ‘bi’) lips (from ‘labial’). You make the sounds by placing your lips together and letting vibration out through the nose. Make sure the rest of your mouth is relaxed when you make this sound - the tongue should feel totally at rest.</string>
    <string name="desc_nsounds">The /n/ is an alveolar nasal - ‘alveolar’ referring to the ‘alveolar ridge’, the ridge near the front of the roof of your mouth. When you make the ‘n’, you should feel the tongue touching the ridge, and the sound coming only out of your nose.</string>
    <string name="desc_ngsounds">The /ŋ/ is a velar nasal - ‘velar’ referring to the soft palate (or ‘velum’), the soft ridge of muscle at the back of the mouth. You can feel the velum by running your finger along the roof of your mouth until you feel some soft muscle at the back of the throat. When you make this sound, the back of the tongue connects with the velum, creating a seal. The sound comes through the nose, and what you get is the /ŋ/. Try it out on the words above.</string>
    <string name="desc_lsounds">The /l/ and /ɫ/ are alveolar lateral approximants. ‘Alveolar’ refers to the ‘alveolar ridge’, the ridge near the front of the roof of your mouth. ‘Lateral’ means that when you touch the tongue to the alveolar ridge, the sound comes out either side of it (as in, ‘laterally’). That’s how you make the sound - just by touching the tip of the tongue to the ridge at the front of the mouth, and letting the sound go out either side of it.</string>
    <string name="desc_darkl">As well as being an alveolar lateral approximant (see above), the dark L (/ɫ/) is also a velar approximant. ‘Velar’ refers to the soft palate (or ‘velum’), the soft ridge of muscle at the back of the mouth. You can feel the velum by running your finger along the roof of your mouth until you feel some soft muscle at the back of the throat. That means that as well as touching at the front of the mouth, the back of your tongue approximates (nearly touches) the back of your throat too. Feel where you might make a /k/ or /g/ sound. That’s where the back of the tongue needs to head towards, while still keeping the tongue tip touching the alveolar ridge.</string>
    <string name="desc_rsound">The /r/ is a postalveolar approximant. ‘Post’ means behind, and ‘alveolar’ refers to the ‘alveolar ridge’, the ridge near the front of the roof of your mouth. That means that to make the /r/, the tongue bunches backwards to a space behind the alveolar ridge, near the roof of your mouth. Try feeling the space behind the alveolar ridge with your finger. That’s where the tongue should be approximating to (nearly touching) to make the /r/.</string>
    <string name="desc_ysound">The /j/ is a palatal approximant, ‘palatal’ referring to the ‘hard palate’ - otherwise known as the roof of your mouth. To make the /j/ sound, the tongue approximates to (nearly touches) the roof of the mouth. At the start of the sound, it feels almost like the /iː/ in ‘easy’, with the tongue high in the mouth. Try feeling the mouth position by copying an /iː/, and trying to mimic the sound.</string>
    <string name="desc_wsound">The /w/ is a labio-velar approximant. ‘Labio’ refers to the lips, and ‘velar’ refers to the soft palate (or ‘velum’), the soft ridge of muscle at the back of the mouth. You can feel the velum by running your finger along the roof of your mouth until you feel some soft muscle at the back of the throat. To make the /w/ sound, the lips nearly touch at the front of the mouth and the back of the tongue approximates to (nearly touches) the velum. The starting position is something the /uː/ in ‘oops’. See if you can use the starting position of an /uː/ to find your way to the sound.</string>
    <string name="desc_schwa">The ‘schwa’ is the most common vowel sound in the British accent. Though it may seem too small to be important, it pops up in many words that you don’t expect. It’s in ‘-a’ endings such as ‘India’ and ‘comma’; in ‘-er’ endings such as ‘better’ and ‘faster’; in ‘com-’ and ‘con-’ beginnings such as ‘complete’ and ‘contain’; in ‘-tion’ endings such as ‘station’ and ‘question’. The schwa is always on the unstressed part of the word. See if you can spot it in the words above.</string>
    <string name="desc_aylips">This vowel is a combination of the /e/ and /ɪ/ sounds, meaning the lips begin in the spread /e/ position and finish in the neutral /ɪ/ position. They should spread at the beginning, then smoothly move to a more relaxed position.</string>
    <string name="desc_ighlips">This vowel is a combination of the /a/ (very close to /æ/) and /ɪ/, meaning the lips begin in the spread /æ/ and finish in the neutral /ɪ/ position. They should spread at the beginning, then smoothly move to a more relaxed position.</string>
    <string name="desc_airlips">This vowel is a combination of the /e/ and /ə/, meaning the lips begin in the spread /e/ and finish in the neutral /ə/ position. They should spread at the beginning, then smoothly move to a more relaxed position.</string>
    <string name="desc_owlips">This vowel is a combination of the /a/ (very close to /æ/) and /ʊ/, meaning the lips begin in the spread /æ/ and finish in a slightly rounded /ʊ/ position. They should spread at the beginning, then glide into a more rounded posture.</string>
    <string name="desc_olips">This vowel is a combination of the /ə/ and /ʊ/, meaning the lips begin in the neutral /ə/ and finish in a slightly rounded /ʊ/ position. They should be relaxed when you start the sound, then glide into a more rounded posture.</string>
    <string name="desc_oylips">This vowel is a combination of the /ɔ/ and /ɪ/, meaning the lips begin in the very rounded /ɔ/ and finish in a relaxed, neutral /ɪ/ position. They should be puckered forward when you start the sound, then glide into a more relaxed posture.</string>
    <string name="desc_ighjaw">This vowel is a combination of the /a/ (very close to /æ/) and /ɪ/, meaning the jaw begins very far open for /æ/ and finishes in a closed /ɪ/ position. The jaw should be 2-3 finger widths apart for the start of the sound, and less than one finger’s width apart at the end.</string>
    <string name="desc_owjaw">This vowel is a combination of the /a/ (very close to /æ/) and /ʊ/, meaning the jaw begins very far open for /æ/ and finishes in a semi-open /ʊ/ position. The jaw should be 2-3 finger widths apart for the start of the sound, and one finger’s width apart at the end.</string>
    <string name="desc_owplace">This vowel is a combination of the /a/ (very close to /æ/) and /ʊ/. The /æ/ (as in ‘cat’) feels like it resonates at the front. Try saying the sound on its own, noticing where the tongue is placed. Next, try the /ʊ/ (as in ‘book’), noticing where that feels like it resonates. Now try moving between them, gliding between the front placement and the back placement.</string>
    <string name="desc_oplace">This vowel is a combination of the /ə/ and /ʊ/. The /ə/ (as in the ‘a’ of ‘comma’) feels like it resonates at the centre of the mouth. Try saying the sound on its own, noticing where the tongue is placed. Next, try the /ʊ/ (as in ‘book’), noticing where that feels like it resonates. Now try moving between them, gliding between the centre and the back of the mouth.</string>
    <string name="desc_earplace">This vowel is a combination of the /ɪ/ and /ə/. The /ɪ/ (as in ‘kit’) feels like it resonates at the front of the mouth. Try saying the sound on its own, noticing where the tongue is placed. Next, try the /ə/ (as in the ‘a’ of ‘comma’), noticing where that feels like it resonates. Now try moving between them, gliding between the front and the centre of the mouth.</string>
    <string name="desc_airplace">This vowel is a combination of the /e/ and /ə/. The /e/ (as in ‘set’) feels like it resonates at the front of the mouth. Try saying the sound on its own, noticing where the tongue is placed. Next, try the /ə/ (as in the ‘a’ of ‘comma’), noticing where that feels like it resonates. Now try moving between them, gliding between the front and the centre of the mouth.</string>
    <string name="desc_oyplace">This vowel is a combination of the /ɔ/ and /ɪ/. The /ɔ/ (as in ‘taught’) feels like it resonates at the back of the mouth. Try saying the sound on its own, noticing where the tongue is placed. Next, try the /ɪ/ (as in ‘kit’), noticing where that feels like it resonates. Now try moving between them, gliding between the back and the front of the mouth.</string>
    
    

</resources>
