<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Practice Words</string>
    <string name="desc_morecoming">There‘s more to say about this sound, so future updates will add more descriptions.</string>
    <string name="desc_diphthongs">Some vowels, like the ‘long’ and ‘short’ ones, choose one position and stick to it throughout. On the word ‘see’, your mouth finds a static position when it hits the ‘ee’, and holds it until the word is done. Diphthongs are vowels which move from one position to another. The vowel /eɪ/ (in ‘say’) starts with an /e/ (in ‘set’) and ends with an /ɪ/ (in ‘sit’). Diphthongs glide from one place to another, like “saaaayyyyy”. Some are obvious, like the ‘ah’ and ‘oo’ in the /aʊ/ in ‘mouth’. Some are more subtle, such as the sliding /eə/ in ‘chair’. Try to feel the beginning and end point of the diphthong vowel in the words above.</string>
    <string name="desc_shortvowels">Short vowels are - no surprises - short. They are quick, sharp, and punchy. When you emphasise a word with a short vowel, you emphasise the consonants, not the vowel. It’s the difference between ‘seat’ and ‘sit’. “Have a seeeeaat!”. “Just sssssit.” Try saying the words sharply, with more emphasis on the consonants.</string>
    <string name="desc_longvowels">Long vowels are - unsurprisingly - long. They are slow, gliding and smooth. When you emphasise a word with a long vowel, you emphasise the vowel, not the consonants which surround it. It’s the difference between ‘foot’ and ‘food’. “My ffffoot!.” “Have some foooood!”. Try making the words above longer, elongating the vowel.</string>
    <string name="desc_openjaw">This vowel uses an open jaw. The mouth should feel quite far open, and may feel quite weird for some speakers. The top and bottom front teeth should be two-three fingers’ widths apart. Try saying the vowel with two or three fingers between your teeth.</string>
    <string name="desc_midjaw">This vowel uses a semi-open jaw. The mouth should feel fairly neutral, as though it were at rest. The top and bottom front teeth should be one finger’s width apart. Try saying the vowel with one finger held between your teeth.</string>
    <string name="desc_closedjaw">This vowel uses a nearly closed jaw. The jaw should be very close to closed, but with a small gap between the teeth. The jaw should be slightly open, but too closed for you to fit a finger between the gap between your teeth.</string>
    <string name="desc_roundedlips">This vowel uses a rounded lip position. The lips should be puckered forward, creating a circular shape far further forward than their normal position. Imagine blowing out a candle, with the lips creating a funnel to direct the air forward. Place your fingers at the corner of your mouth. When you make the sound, you should notice the muscles in the lips working and pushing the mouth forwards.</string>
    <string name="desc_neutrallips">This mouth uses a neutral lip position. The lips should be totally relaxed. This may feel very strange for some accents. But for this sound, the lazier the lips, the better sound you get. Even the muscles around the lips are totally relaxed. Try making the sound and massaging the lips with your fingers to stop the lips overworking.</string>
    <string name="desc_spreadlips">This mouth uses a spread lip position. The lips should be engaged upwards and sideways into a smile. In a mirror, you should notice that you can see lots of your top row of teeth. Try making the sound with your fingers feeling the muscles between your lips and your cheekbones. There should be a sensation of muscles working gently below your fingers.</string>
    <string name="desc_placementback">All vowels feel different: they have different resonances in the mouth. On the /iː/ sound (‘ee’), you can feel vibrations at the front of the mouth. On the other hand, the /ɔː/ (‘or’) sound feels very far back. This vowel should feel as though it is at the back, similar to the /ɔː/. You should notice that the tongue feels engaged in a downward direction, with the sound resonating deep in the throat. Try making the sound with this in mind.</string>
    <string name="desc_placementcentral">All vowels feel different: they have different resonances in the mouth. On the /iː/ sound (‘ee’), you can feel vibrations at the front of the mouth. On the other hand, the /ɔː/ (‘or’) sound feels very far back. This vowel should feel as though it is in the centre of the mouth. You should notice that the tongue feels very relaxed and neutral, with the tongue tip touching behind the bottom row of teeth. Try making the sound with this in mind.</string>
    <string name="desc_placementfront">All vowels feel different: they have different resonances in the mouth. On the /iː/ sound (‘ee’), you can feel vibrations at the front of the mouth. On the other hand, the /ɔː/ (‘or’) sound feels very far back. This vowel feels as though it is at the front, similar to the /iː/. You should notice that the tongue feels engaged in a forward direction, with the tongue tip touching behind the bottom row of teeth. Try making the sound with this in mind.</string>
    <string name="desc_fricatve">A fricative is a consonant that uses air pressure and friction to create sound. On each fricative, you blow out air and create friction by placing together two parts of the mouth. For the /f/ sound, the lower lip and the teeth come together. For the /s/ sound, the tongue creates friction just behind the upper teeth. Fricatives can be dragged out, and can last a long time, such as in “ssssssssooooo”. Other consonants, like plosives, are harder and can’t be dragged. Try extending and dragging out the fricative consonant in the words above.</string>
    <string name="desc_plosive">Plosives are explosions. They use a build-up of pressure, then an explosive release, to create sound. For a /p/ sound, the pressure builds behind the lips, then releases all at once in a ‘pop’. For a ‘t’ sound, the pressure builds between the tongue and the top teeth, then does the same. They are different from fricatives, which have no build-up of pressure. Plosives are punchier and sharper. On the words above, try making the plosive consonants sharper and punchier.</string>
    <string name="desc_affricate">Affricates are mixes between plosives and fricatives. They have the explosive quality of the plosives, and the dragged-out quality of the fricatives. The /tʃ/ (‘ch’) sound is a mix between a /t/ and a /ʃ/ (‘sh’), with the strong start of the ‘t’ and the longer ending of the ‘sh’. The /dʒ/ (‘j’) sound is a mix between the /d/ and the /ʒ/ (‘zh’ in measure). Make sure the affricates feel punchier than the fricatives - hit them hard at the beginnings.</string>
    <string name="desc_nasal">Most sounds are created in the throat, and leave through the mouth. But nasal consonants are different. They are the only sounds which leave through the nose, creating a distinctive muffled sound. Try closing one nostril with your finger and making a /m/ (‘mmm’) sound. You will feel the vibrations on your finger. Now try a /d/ (‘duh’) sound. You should feel far less vibration, or none at all. Keep your finger on your nose, and try to feel the nasality of each of the consonants above.</string>
    <string name="desc_approximant">Most consonants create sound by touching something to something else. For the /f/, the lower lips touch the teeth. But approximants don’t use contact: they move muscles closer to each other, narrowing the vocal tract to create the sound. They don’t touch, they approximate. For the /w/, the lips narrow at the front of the mouth. For the /r/, the tongue bunches up and approximates to the roof of the mouth. The /l/ and /ɫ/ (‘light’ and ‘still’) create narrowing by touching the roof of the mouth with the tongue. Try each sound in the words above, noticing the mouth and throat narrowing at the crucial moment.</string>
    <string name="desc_voiced">Voiced consonants use vocal fold vibration to make the sound. That means that, when you say this consonant, you should be feeling vibrations inside your throat. Take a finger and place it on your throat, and make a ‘mmm’ sound. You should feel a humming sensation. Next, make the sound above. You should feel the same sensation. Try the words above, feeling the vibrations on each voiced sound.</string>
    <string name="desc_unvoiced">Unvoiced consonants use no vocal fold vibration to make the sound. That means that, when you say this consonant you should feel no vibrations in the throat. Take a finger and place it on your throat, and make a ‘shh’ sound. You should feel no vibrations on the throat, unlike the voiced consonants, which vibrate heavily. Make the sound above. With your finger on your throat, you should feel no vibration at all. Try the words above, noticing the lack of vibration.</string>
</resources>
